<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Community &#8211; Burpeezoid</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/community/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2018 14:29:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.6.11</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Nude CrossFit: This Box Supposedly Does Nude Workouts</title>
		<link>/2014/05/30/nude-crossfit-this-box-supposedly-does-nude-workouts/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2014 15:53:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BZADMIN]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Community Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CrossFit]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=501</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Why stop at taking your shirt off when you can also take your shorts and underwear off as well? Spartan Mentality CrossFit in Aarhus, Denmark reportedly offers a different kind of workout: one that doesn’t involve clothes. The nude workouts are held Sunday evenings with twelve dudes initially joining the program. No word yet if &#8230; <a href="/2014/05/30/nude-crossfit-this-box-supposedly-does-nude-workouts/" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Nude CrossFit: This Box Supposedly Does Nude Workouts</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/nude-crossfit-2-930x360c.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-502" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/nude-crossfit-2-930x360c.jpg" alt="nude-crossfit-2-930x360c" width="930" height="360" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/nude-crossfit-2-930x360c.jpg 930w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/03/nude-crossfit-2-930x360c-300x116.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 930px) 100vw, 930px" /></a></p>
<p>Why stop at taking your shirt off when you can also take your shorts and underwear off as well? <a href="http://www.spartanmentality.dk/" target="_blank">Spartan Mentality CrossFit</a> in Aarhus, Denmark reportedly offers a different kind of workout: one that doesn’t involve clothes.</p>
<p>The nude workouts are held Sunday evenings with twelve dudes initially joining the program. No word yet if any ladies are planning to join. *crosses fingers* “People are already so scantily clad at Crossfit that we thought we might as well throw the rest away,” says Steffen Haldrup Andersen, creator and director of the naked Crossfit team.</p>
<p>Unfortunately – or fortunately, depending on how you look at it – Nude CrossFit was actually an April Fool’s joke that people got a little too excited (no pun intended) about. <a href="http://cphpost.dk/news/the-nude-crossfit-sessions-going-viral-are-a-hoax.9650.html" target="_blank">The Copenhagen Post</a> reports:</p>
<blockquote><p>Nude crossfit was an April Fool’s joke that ran a little too far, explains Rune Jensen, the co-owner and an instructor at Spartan Mentality Crossfit in Aarhus.</p>
<p>“It started out as an April Fool’s joke that got too much attention,” he said.</p>
<p>“We then actually decided to start up the nude sessions, but in the end there was too much media focus on us. It all got a little too comical and we changed our minds. I have no idea how the story went viral.”</p>
<p>The April Fool’s story also said that exercises included the kettlebell – a cast-iron ball with a handle that you swing up above your head and back down between your legs – as well as rope-climbing (but watch out for that rope burn!)</p></blockquote>
<p><a href="http://www.curatorscode.org/">↬</a> <a href="http://instinctmagazine.com/post/crossfit-gym-now-offers-nude-workouts-nsfw">Instinct Magazine</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
