<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Events &#8211; Burpeezoid</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/articles-videos/events/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2018 14:29:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.6.11</generator>
	<item>
		<title>The Beginner’s Guide To The National Pro Grid League</title>
		<link>/2014/08/18/the-beginners-guide-to-the-national-pro-grid-league/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2014 14:29:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BZADMIN]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=476</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In December of 2013, CrossFit Games’ executive producer and co-director, Tony Budding left to form a new competition. He had been working with CrossFit Inc. for the last 10 years, serving as a coach, affiliate director, and media director before leaving to open a new chapter in functional fitness’ book: The National Pro Grid League (NPGL.) &#8230; <a href="/2014/08/18/the-beginners-guide-to-the-national-pro-grid-league/" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">The Beginner’s Guide To The National Pro Grid League</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/npgl31-930x360c.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-481" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/npgl31-930x360c.jpg" alt="npgl31-930x360c" width="930" height="360" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/npgl31-930x360c.jpg 930w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/03/npgl31-930x360c-300x116.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 930px) 100vw, 930px" /></a></p>
<p>In December of 2013, CrossFit Games’ executive producer and co-director, Tony Budding left to form a new competition. He had been working with CrossFit Inc. for the last 10 years, serving as a coach, affiliate director, and media director before leaving to open a new chapter in functional fitness’ book: <a href="https://www.npgl.com/" target="_blank" class="broken_link">The National Pro Grid League</a> (NPGL.)</p>
<p>Unlike the CrossFit Games, Budding sees the NPGL as “the world’s first professional spectator sport with co-ed teams competing in human performance races.” Think of it as the NBA or NFL of functional fitness as opposed to the CrossFit Games being like the Olympics. Whereas the Games only gives out prize money to the top 10 individuals and top three teams, the NPGL professionalizes its athletes, meaning every team member gets paid. The eight inaugural teams in the league will pay their athletes a minimum of $2,500 per match. Teams are also city or region based to encourage a strong following from their respective home bases (imagine LA visiting New York)</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/npgl1.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-478" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/npgl1.jpg" alt="npgl1" width="740" height="415" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/npgl1.jpg 740w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/03/npgl1-300x168.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 740px) 100vw, 740px" /></a></p>
<p>Also unlike the Games, the NPGL’s events are announced – allowing the teams to plan, strategize, and practice ahead of time. In the matches themselves, two teams of 10 (five men, five women, with a mandatory one male and one female athlete over the age of 40) will compete over 11 matches spanning two hours in a place they call the Grid. They will then do a series of CrossFit-inspired workouts like thrusters, burpees, muscle-ups, and rope climbs, allowing substitutions to take place during the course of the match. The winning team to reach the finish line for each match receives two points, while the losing team receives 1 point. Any team who receives a DNF will get no points.</p>
<p>Confused? Don’t be. They even have a fancy scoreboard that updates with each athlete’s every rep, helping spectators keep track of the action. It’s a new development that NPGL organizers are banking on to help make functional fitness a spectator sport. Here, check it out:</p>
<p>While many high-profile CrossFit athletes, like Annie Thorisdottir, Andrea Ager, Kenny Leverich, and Khan Porter, have seen NPGL’s light and jumped on the bandwagon, many of Budding’s former colleagues at CrossFit Inc. think otherwise. Russ Green, CrossFit’s spokesperson, has been going around social media attempting to distance the Sport of Fitness from the up-and-coming league.</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/npgl4.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-479" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/npgl4.jpg" alt="npgl4" width="590" height="229" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/npgl4.jpg 590w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/03/npgl4-300x116.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 590px) 100vw, 590px" /></a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/npgl5.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-480" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/npgl5.jpg" alt="npgl5" width="460" height="239" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/npgl5.jpg 460w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/03/npgl5-300x156.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 460px) 100vw, 460px" /></a></p>
<p>Despite having received no blessing from the company he helped build, Budding knows very well that CrossFit and the NPGL are two different things. While one is focused purely on fitness, the other is aimed towards sponsors, endorsements, ticket sales, and TV ratings (NBC will be covering the league’s playoffs in October, while the Games are relegated to ESPN2.) And for Budding, that’s not necessarily a bad thing.</p>
<p>“We are a spectator sport which means we exist for the fans,” he says. “Our goal is to make our teams and our athletes so compelling, so exciting, so speaking for the metropolitan area that they’re from, that people want to just be fans of the team.”</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/npgl.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-477" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/npgl.jpg" alt="NPGL - Grid League Photos - Miami Draft 2014" width="2001" height="1334" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/npgl.jpg 2001w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/03/npgl-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/03/npgl-1024x683.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 2001px) 100vw, 2001px" /></a></p>
<p>The question now is: Will fans get into the NPGL the way they are now coming in droves to the CrossFit Games? We’ll find out soon enough. The National Pro Grid League kicks off its inaugural match on Tuesday, August 19<sup>th</sup>, 7pm with the New York Rhinos facing off against the LA Reign at Madison Square Garden.</p>
<p>Photo credit 1: <a href="https://www.npgl.com/" target="_blank" class="broken_link">NPGL</a>, Photo credit 2: <a href="http://blog.fattonybmx.com/grid-league-photos/" target="_blank">Fat Tony</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
